hiddenbrains.com 2019-04-01

# Privacy Statement of Hidden brains

## PRIVACY POLICY OF HIDDEN BRAINS AS PER I.T.ACT, 2000

We at Hidden Brains (Hidden Brains Infotech Pvt. Ltd. and Hidden Brains Infotech LLC), are committed to protecting your privacy. This Privacy Policy applies to our website ([www.hiddenbrains.com](https://www.hiddenbrains.com/)) and our Subscription Service (Subscription for regular IT news and happenings), including our associated mobile applications (Mobile Apps) owned and controlled by Hidden Brains. This Privacy Policy governs our data collection, processing and usage practices. It also describes your choices regarding use, access and correction of your personal information. If you do not agree with the data practices described in this Privacy Policy, you should not use the Websites or the Subscription Service. 

This legal document is an electronic record in terms of India’s Information Technology Act, 2000, and rules there under as applicable and the amended provisions pertaining to electronic records in various statutes as amended by the Information Technology Act, 2000. This electronic record is generated by a computer system and does not require any physical or digital signatures.

This legal document is published in accordance with the provisions of Rule 4 of the Information Technology (Reasonable security practices and procedures and sensitive personal data or information) Rules, 2011 of Information Technology Act, 2000 amended through Information Technology Amendment Act, 2008 that require publishing the privacy policy for access or usage of [www.hiddenbrains.com](https://www.hiddenbrains.com/) (“HiddenBrains” or “website”).

This privacy policy applies to all users and subscribers of our websites.

By using this website, or completing the contact registration process through offline mode, you agree and acknowledge that you have carefully read this privacy policy and accepted this agreement.

References in these Terms to "we" or "us" or “website” or “company” or “HiddenBrains” are references to www.hiddenbrains.com and “you” as subscriber/user of a website.

## Privacy Preamble

While providing information for various web development services, the issue of online privacy is extremely crucial for Hidden Brains, which is committed for safeguarding the information provided by its users. We are dedicated to create a reasonably secured environment for our users.

Respecting privacy of its online users while providing top-of-the-line services have always been the core strategies of Hidden Brains. Our Privacy Policy gives users a view of the Privacy Practices followed by us and assures them of safe passage through the website.

At the same time, we would like to make it clear that our website may provide links to other websites/apps that are governed by their own Privacy Policies and we do not take responsibility for the security and privacy provided by these sites/apps. This may include but are not limited to payment gateway sites. Users are urged to familiarize themselves with its Privacy Policy as well the policies of the third party sites/apps that collect personally identifiable information.

When you provide us with your personal data, you are agreeing to the rules and regulations stipulated under our Privacy Policy and are bound by it. If you do not agree to our Policy then please do not use our website.

## THE PRIVACY POLICY SHALL BE GOVERNED IN THESE AREAS

  1. **Information we may collect about you**
    * **Information you give us:** During the process of Contact us/get in touch, you will be requested to complete a registration form asking for basic online contact information about yourself or provide us with your details over the phone, for example when you request for a quote on specific development service, register to attend one of our events (whether as a delegate, exhibitor or attendee) or subscribe to our mailing list. This information might include your name, address, email address, phone number and other relevant information. You agree and acknowledge that when we receive e-mails from you, we may retain the content of any e-mail messages sent to us, as well as details of your e-mail address. You further agree and acknowledge that we shall use your email ID and mobile number information for sending promotional/informational messages.
    * **Information we collect about you:** We will collect any information contained in any correspondence between you and us via contact forms on websites, and emails or telephone calls. 

We may collect, for the purposes of service & solutions promotions and any events that we exhibit or participate, information about your location in and engagement with the event.

We collect information about you visiting our website and how you use it. This may include your IP address, geographical location, device information, browser type, referral source, length of visit, operating system, number of page views, which pages you viewed and similar information. This information may be collected by a third party website analytics service provider on our behalf and/or may be collected using cookies. We also use cookies and pixels in our emails to track delivery and open rates, the results of which are stored against your email address and profile.

We use third party analytics services for more detailed analytics purposes. It is important for us to inform you that we will have limited control over these Analytics and therefore you clearly agree and acknowledge that we shall not be held responsible for privacy issues relating to the same.

    * **Information we receive from third parties:** We may collect information about you from third parties that we work closely with for the purposes of delivering to you the services rendered by us. Third party entities may collect information directly from your websites or your digital presence. We may also receive information about you from third parties where you have consented to such third party sharing your information.
  2. **How we use information about you**
    * We may use your information for the following purposes, depending on the relationship we have with you. Prior to submitting your personal data to us, we will provide you more specific information where necessary about how we will use your data, and link you to this privacy policy. 
**We use personal data to:** | **The purpose of this is:** | **The applicable legal basis:**  
---|---|---  
Provide you with information that you have requested from us, in relation to development services and other services we provide (for example online webinars, news and promotional materials). | We will need to use your contact details to keep you updated about the products or services you have indicated you are interested in. | By specifically requesting information from us, you are consenting to us using your personal data for the purposes of communicating such information to you.  
To invite you to meet us at the events and exhibitions.  | We will need to use your details for planning of business meeting.  | Where you have registered to attend or meet at an event, we need to use your personal data in this way to perform our business ties and meetings.  
Analyse user traffic to measure use of our websites and improve their content. | We may use information such as your IP address for analytical purposes of our pages, this could also include improving the content of our websites and services. | We have identified web analytics as a legitimate interest of our business, and allow us to better meet your needs as a customer.  
To comply with or abide by legal obligations or requirements. | We may need to use or process your personal data to comply with some legal requirements. | Where we need to process your data for these reasons, the legal basis will be compliance with a legal obligation.  
  
You can find out more information on the privacy notice provided at the time you submit your data to us or in your contract with us (if applicable).

  3. **Who we might share your data with**

In certain circumstances we may share your personal information with:

    * Government authorities for legal compliances and processes.
    * Third party vendors that could help you in your projects and business, with your consent.
    * Website users through testimonials and portfolio, with your consent.
    * Event organizer’s portal that ask for specific information to send meeting invitations.
    * Internal references and contacts that could help you in your business, with mutual consent of the both parties.
    * New customers that ask for region-specific references, with your consent.
    * AWS if you have opted for Cloud services.
    * Any other third parties where necessary to enable us to enforce our legal rights, or to protect the rights, property or safety of our employees or where such disclosure may be permitted or required by law.
  4. **Cookies**

We use cookies to ensure that you get the most out of our site. Cookies are small text files which we store on the device you use to access the site. Cookies allow us to monitor your use of the software and simplify your use of the site. If you do not wish for cookies to be installed on your device, you can change the settings on your browser or device to reject cookies. For more information about how to reject cookies using your internet browser settings please consult the “Help” section of your internet browser (or alternatively visit [http://www.aboutcookies.org](http://www.aboutcookies.org/)). Please note that, if you set your Internet browser to reject cookies, you may not be able to access all of the functions of our websites.

  5. **Third Party Content, Sites, and Contributions**

Some of our websites may contain content and links to other websites or apps that are operated by third parties. We don’t control these third party websites or apps (including whether or not they store cookies) and this Privacy Policy does not apply to them. Please consult the terms and conditions and Privacy Policy of the relevant third party website or app to find out how that site/app collects and uses your information and to establish whether and for what purpose they use cookies.

  6. **How we look after your data and how long we keep it for**

We use a variety of technological and operational security measures to protect your information against any unauthorized access to, unlawful use of and modification and destruction of any personal data we store.

Transmission of information over the internet can be insecure, and although we employ measures to protect your information from unauthorized access, we cannot always guarantee the security of information sent over the internet.

  7. **Where we store your information**

Where you are interacting with a Hidden Brains, our local High-end IBM cluster servers & IBM Storage servers are secured with Sonic wall firewall and online servers are on secured cloud platforms and on top of that Hidden Brains has configured some extra layer of data protection and security requirement.

Hidden Brains has a systematic and ongoing approach for managing information security that affect the confidentiality, integrity, and availability of company and customer information.

we will take all steps necessary to ensure that any of your information is adequately protected and processed in accordance with this Privacy Policy, and where necessary, we put in place relevant safeguards to ensure the safe processing of your data.

  8. **Your rights in relation to your Personal Data**

You have the right to:

    * Request a copy of the personal data that we keep about you, by making a request in writing to the Data Protection Officer. You can ask us to provide the data in a commonly used machine readable format.
    * Contact the Data Protection Officer if you are concerned that any of the information we hold on you is incorrect, to have that data corrected.
    * Contact the Data Protection Officer to ask us to stop processing your data, or withdraw consent where we are relying on consent as the legal basis for any processing of your data.
    * Contact the Data Protection Officer to request that we delete your personal data.

## Choice/Opt-out

Once you are registered at the our site, you will have the option at any stage to inform us that you no longer wish to receive future services, e-mails and you may “unsubscribe” by sending unsubscribe request. Further, as per Rule 5(7) of the India’s Information Technology (Reasonable security practices and procedures and sensitive personal data or information) Rules, 2011 of Information Technology Act, 2000 amended through Information Technology Amendment Act, 2008, you have an option to withdraw your consent for use of your sensitive personal data given earlier to us. Such withdrawal of consent shall be sent in writing to our registered address.

**Reasonable Security Practices As per I.T.Act, 2000 and its Rules** We have implemented reasonable security practices as per Rule 8 of the India’s Information Technology (Reasonable security practices and procedures and sensitive personal data or information) Rules, 2011 of Information Technology Act, 2000 amended through Information Technology Amendment Act, 2008.

We have implemented stringent, internationally acceptable standards of technology, managerial security, technical security, operational security and physical security in order to protect your personally identifiable information from loss, misuse, disclosure, alteration or destruction. The data resides behind a firewall, with access restricted to our authorized personnel’s only.

We have implemented “Reasonable Security Practices” as required by the India’s Information Technology Act, 2000 rules including any amendment in the said Act and its rules. By complying with such provisions, We assure you proper care and control over our I.T. and Security operations as required under relevant sections mainly section 43, 43A, 45, 66,72A & 85 of I.T.Act, 2000 and I.T.A.A, 2008 including related rules and therefore you agree that we shall not be held responsible for any fraudulent/criminal activity with regards to your sensitive personal information stored in our website.

By using this website you agree that we shall not be held responsible for any uncontrollable security attacks and in such cases you agree that we shall not be held responsible for any type of financial losses, loss of opportunity, legal cost, attorney’s fees, business losses, reputation loss, direct and indirect losses that may occur to you as per the Provisions of Section 43, 43A and 45 of Information Technology Act, 2000 including any amendments in the said Act and any other laws of India for the time being in force.

You further agree that our management shall not be held responsible directly or indirectly for any cyber-crime related criminal liabilities under I.T.Act,2000 relating to your information as you have agreed and acknowledged that our management complies with due diligence (care & controls) requirements of I.T.Act,2000 including its rules and amendments.

## Our reasonable security controls include but not limited to following:

  * Software firewall
  * HTTPS Connection Encrypted (TLS_ECDHE_RSA_WITH_AES_256_GCM_SHA384, 256 bit keys, TLS1.2)
  * Cyber Law & Security Compliance intimation letters to our team
  * Cyber Law & Security Awareness for our team by professional cyber lawyers and information security consultant’s firm

Further, you also agree and acknowledge that our management shall never be held responsible regarding privacy of your sensitive personal data in case of sharing your sensitive personal data to any authorized cyber investigation agency of appropriate government authorities as required under sections 67C, 69, 69A, 69B, 70B, 79 and 80 of I.T.Act,2000 including its amendments and rules.

## Grievance Redressal

If you have any questions or grievances regarding the privacy statement, practices of the site, or any other transaction issue, please contact our grievance officer on [privacy@hiddenbrains.in](mailto:privacy@hiddenbrains.in)

We have appointed our grievance officer as per Rule 5 (9) of the Information Technology (Reasonable security practices and procedures and sensitive personal data or information) Rules, 2011 of Information Technology Act, 2000 amended through Information Technology Amendment Act, 2008.

## Amendments to these Policies

We reserve the right to amend these policies from time to time. When we make a change we will update this page of the Website. We recommend that you revisit this page from time to time so as to ensure that you are aware of any changes that we have made to these Policies.

## Applicable Laws & Jurisdiction

You agree and acknowledge that this privacy policy agreement shall be governed by Laws of India without any conflict of laws. Further, you agree and acknowledge that Indian courts located in city of Ahmedabad , State of Gujarat shall have jurisdiction for any matters relating to this privacy policy. If you don’t agree then you shall not use this website.
